The reason number one why people tell us
they don't subscribe is because they the
free tier is good enough. Our philosophy
is that literally we want to do
something about it, but that something
is not making the free tier worse. It's
trying to provide more value and really
diversify the subscription offer.
>> Hello. I'm your host David Barnard. My
guest today is Geo Conte Stable, VP of
product at Life360.
On the podcast, I talked with Geo about
making growth everyone's job.
Protecting the free experience even when
it hurts conversion.
And why inconclusive experiments are the
only kind he hates.
Hey Geo, thanks so much for joining me
on the podcast today.
>> Hey David, thank you for having me and
long time fan of the podcast of Revenue
Cat. So I'm very happy to be here.
>> Oh, thanks. Thanks. So so many people in
the industry
lean on Duolingo as kind of the the
superstar example of a subscription app
that's, you know, broken out success and
uh publicly traded and you know, done
really well and everything. And I think
way too many people sleep on Life360.
Uh it's just such an incredible app. I
mean, in some ways, you know, I think
we'll get into this, but you probably
have a stronger moat, a like more
dedicated users. Like there's so much
going on with Life360
um that I think more people just need to
know about. So I'm excited to have you
on the podcast and I wanted to kick it
off because a lot of people might not be
familiar with Life360, giving you a
chance to kind of share some numbers,
humble brag a little bit. You know, it's
a publicly traded company, so they can
go read your filings and they can look
at the stock performance and stuff like
that, but uh doesn't always tell the
whole story. So uh
yeah, tell it tell us about Life360.
>> For sure, for sure. And uh I definitely
agree we're a kind of a sleeping giant
in a way. And literally the company's
been around for a long time, about 15
years. Uh we've been public in the US
for for a couple of years now. You know,
we're a um uh, the
and peace of mind app primarily for
families and we interpret family in a
very broad way, basically helping you
keep your people, pets, and things and
things that you care about, um, safe and
knowing, uh, where they are. Uh, in
terms of size, we we have about, close
to 100 million monthly active users, uh,
I would say close to half of those in
the US and a half internationally. We
only started really growing
internationally in the last couple of
years and naturally is the grow the
fastest growing market for us as it
should be. You know, in terms of, uh,
subscription, you know, this is, I
think, an interesting point to make. We
have a, um, around 3 million active
subscribers. Now, if that is low
compared to the 100 million MAU, it is
because, uh, every subscription is, uh,
actually used by four people, you know,
on average. So, when you subscribe, your
circle, uh, which is often your family,
but could be anyone, gets the benefits.
Uh, so, that means about 12 million
people in reality, you know, uh, benefit
of our subscription.
>> Yeah, that's amazing. I want to dig more
into freemium in a minute, but I'll
rattle off a couple of more numbers from
your, I know by the time this
is released, you'll have announced new
public numbers, but as of your last
quarterly results, you're closing in on
500 million dollars a year in revenue.
Again, sleeping giant, not many people
in the subscription app industry realize
just how big you are.
Uh, and then it's the stock is listed in
the Australian market, so I forget the
exact Australian dollars, but in US
dollars, it's almost a 4 billion dollar,
uh, market cap of the company. So, just
incredible numbers and, you know, uh,
again, just something I think too many
people in the industry sleep on. I
wanted to dive into your thoughts on
subscription growth as a system. So many
apps growth as a team and they maybe
have some systems, but I know you think
about it at a much higher level, so I
wanted you to get an opportunity to
really share that broader perspective
that you bring to the company inside
Life360.
>> I would say the main point you you kind
of already made it. You know, I think
the most important thing if we're for
growth not to be just a team. And to be
honest, we started with that. We started
with a growth team,
but really a system and for everyone in
the company to believe that growth is
part of their job, right? And naturally,
when I talk about growth, I'm talking
about revenue growth, which in our case
can be subscription, can be ads, can be
device sales. You know, we have a Tile
and Page GPS, which are devices to track
things and pets. But it could also be
user growth, right? Which is naturally
super important. Being a system a
systematic
experimentation program at scale was, if
you want, the first step. What we're
doing now, which is I think is is the
real exciting part. And the first part
was naturally very very positive for us.
We're trying to build the tools and AI,
you know, is going to is having a very
very big role there. The gigantic tools
to allow every team to contribute to the
experimentation program, right? And so,
ideally, everyone in the company thinks
that growth is part of what they do. And
ideally, everyone in the company
allocates part of the bandwidth to
experimentation in that sense. And I
think that's where really becomes
powerful because if you align the whole
company behind top line metrics,
probably, you know, revenue growth
metric and a and a user growth metric.
And you allow all of them to then align
behind sub metrics that they can really
influence. And you give them the tools
and the mindset and the mandate and the
freedom to run their own
experimentation, that's where you get
basically a giant experimentation
machine that goes, you know, well beyond
what a what a team can do.
>> Yeah, do you have any specific examples
of of teams that maybe wouldn't normally
be thought of as part of the growth team
or like experiments? Like is your, you
you a service team? Are they running
experiments on kind of user
satisfaction? Like any any examples?
>> Yeah, they they are for sure. I can tell
you, for example, our finance team,
right? Our finance team automated, you
know, if you want a lot of the more kind
of if you
routine
work, and then they they build tools
that really allow them to
mine for information and provide, you
know, insight that can drive real, you
know, user breakthroughs in terms of
pricing, in terms of tearing, in terms
of what we put in our subscription
tiers, etc., etc., right? So, they
definitely very progressive in that
sense. Our our, you know, people team,
yeah, right? Our HR team, you know,
everything from the way they they hire
to the way they evaluate performance, to
the way they look at organization has a
growth a growth angle, if you want,
right? So, I would say it's definitely a
work in progress. I would not say we're
there all the way there. I would not say
we're perfect at all. But the idea is,
how can we align everyone, you know,
beyond our our goals? And then we say
publicly that, you know, we want to to
be a 150 million MAU company. We want to
be a billion-dollar revenue company, you
know, in the next couple of years. And
so, how do we allow align everyone
behind those goals and give them the
tools to to help achieve them.
>> What does that look like on a staffing
perspective, a team-by-team perspective?
Are there are there kind of growth leads
inside engineering, inside finance that
kind of help drive the ship, or is it
just a culture thing where everybody
internally is just growth, growth,
growth? How how does that actually play
out? Like, how how would somebody
replicate this culture you're building?
>> I would say that we we have functions,
mostly the product development ones,
where there are people that have a kind
of a more explicit growth mandate. I
would say for other teams, we don't have
that, but we really relied on we we call
them builders, which I think is is
becoming pretty common now, you know, in
the AI native organizations. It's really
people that have the right mindset, and
they want to, you know, muck around the
stools and they, you know, they really
want to figure out how to do things
faster, how to help growth, etc., etc.
And then they, you know, the idea is to
give them the tools
and the training. You know, we have
programs that specifically train people
for this. We have a fellowship program
where basically you can raise your hand
and say for the next 3 months, instead
of doing my job, I want to go and figure
out how to make my team faster, how to
use technology to make my team faster.
We have different things that we do to
to really help people with that kind of
mindset to do that. But I will say that
overall we looking for them to emerge
and self-select and and kind of start
getting things done.
>> Yeah, that's incredible. I mean, the the
term I've heard used a lot lately is
agency. It's like the best people on a
team are the ones who feel like they can
make a difference and then go start
making a difference. But it does take
the right kind of culture and top-down
leadership of of not micromanaging and
kind of celebrating the wins and
empowering employees to do those kind of
things. So it's really cool to hear that
that that's how you're running it. And
again, such a big organization doing so
much revenue like to be able to continue
operating like that and have that
entrepreneurial mindset all the way up
and down the stack is really cool. A few
more things on on growth. One of the
things you shared with me in prepping
for this is is a kind of equation that
you think about the mechanics of
velocity plus win rate delivers
compounded growth.
>> So we don't think of experimentation as
a series of experiments, but we think as
a portfolio and a learning portfolio if
you want. And you know, very very
simply, you know, there are three levers
that you can pull in terms of
effectiveness of the program. Velocity,
you know, how many experiments
do you ship? Win rate, you know, what
percentage of those,
you know, are successful? But
there is a caveat there that I will go
through now. And they with win, right?
Basically, what we're trying to do now
is increase velocity mostly through AI
while maintaining win rate and average
win win value roughly roughly stable,
right? That's a kind of a first step for
us in going through this
AI transformation. When I say that there
is a caveat for win rate is because
experiment The only experiments that we
are sad about is an experiment that is
inconclusive, right? Then we feel we we
we wasted our time or we didn't set up
the experiment correctly or the
hypothesis was not right because we we
took a bunch of time and a bunch of
effort and we didn't get statistic
results in in any form. If we win, it's
usually a good thing, you know, we we we
call it, we celebrate, we scale it, we
most likely also learn something, so we
will do more experiments. If we lost,
then well, then we just learn something.
We prove or disprove an hypothesis. And
then, you know, the decision could be,
okay, this
specific line of experimentation doesn't
have value today. We should do something
else. Or most likely, it is, well, you
know what? Yeah, it didn't work, but it
worked well for users that live in the
suburbs and have been into in the
platform for at least a month and have a
dog, right? You know, what can we do
about that, right? And usually there are
ideas that that come out of that, right?
And so, it's super important then to go
very deep in terms of how you look at
the wins and losses, right? And
generally speaking, we built a I would
say not not perfect again, but pretty
solid way to a predict the impact of
experiments. And then once we run an
experiment to really segment and
understand why things are happening. And
that naturally helps in
you know, then creating more experiments
and kind of having this portfolio
approach. In a portfolio, you know, some
will win, some will lose. The important
thing is that you you get enough big
wins to to drive growth. And when you
lose, you you get some good learning.
>> Yeah, I I love that you framed learnings
per quarter as a core product metric
versus
wins per quarter or growth per quarter.
Uh it sounds like that was a very
intentional framing. And And do you
actually I mean are teams judged on
that? Is that like a KPI? Is that a a
metric that is is measured across teams
inside Life360, or is that just kind of
like more an operating principle?
>> Is that a very good principle? It's
something that we measure it. I would
like to tell you that is the the core
KPI, but no, revenue
is the core KPI that the teams are
judged on. But it definitely we So, what
what we do is we measure the amount of
inconclusive test, and we we think about
how can we can reduce that. And we we
make sure that when there is a lose
a loss, we we do have the learnings, and
we do have a time to think about it and
act on them.
>> I loved your framing earlier, too, that
even if an experiment fails, if you
learn, it can be really powerful. And
the thing you mentioned is like maybe it
just works for pet owners in suburban,
small town, or whatever. One, like
what's the system you created to to be
able to dig that deep into segmentation?
And then two, do you then take some of
those even tiny segments and do some
customized personalized things for those
segments?
>> Yes. Yes, absolutely. I can talk a bit a
bit about these and also about what
we're doing with machine learning, which
is very very very connected to this.
Being able to kind of look and act on
those segments, that's essentially data
science and data
questions. We we did a I think a lot of
strides in the last couple of years. We
have a very very competent data science
and data engineering and data analytics
team. The tools that we use are, you
know, I I would say tools that most
companies use, you know, from Databricks
to Statsig. We have some homegrown
tools, but but really infrastructure is
pretty standard. It's really is more
about, I would say, the understanding
and knowledge of the user, right? So, we
naturally, beside having a lot of data,
we also spend a lot of time talking to
users. I would say a good understanding
of the main use cases. And so, often
when we read an experiment and we get
data, it's not just some automated
system, although increasingly that's the
case, that tell us, "Oh, this is
interesting." It's really someone that
knows the user and the platform and the
product very well that says, "Oh, this
is happening, you know, I think it
that's the reason why, right? Because
you already seen this in other cases,
etc., etc." So, that's kind of on the
understanding. On the then acting on it,
there are two ways. So, one is
deliver
specific value, specific features
that are aimed at sub audiences, I would
say, or I would say parts of our core
audience. So, for example, we're doing a
lot of work on pets. Why? Because
about 80% of our families with kids that
use our platform also have a pet. So,
there is a huge overlap, you know, as
you can imagine. And also because we
have all the we have a lot of audiences
on the platform that are not necessary,
you know, this nuclear family, couples,
for example. A lot of them have pets,
right? And maybe they're not so
interested in some of our core features
that are like driving safety or things
that, you know, more family oriented.
But if you add value, you know, for pet
owners, we make the platform better for
them. We can make, you know, they
subscribe, etc., etc., right? So, we
think about those audiences. The second,
which is the most exciting, is that in
the last year we started building
machine learning targeting and
orchestration system that basically does
a lot of those things automatically,
learns from from the data, and allows us
to target those experiences in a much
more accurate way. So, in that example
before, will we go and we build and
build a big feature for a micro
audience? No, probably. But we can know
that that audience responds better to
certain things, and we can target
promotions,
we can feature education and other
things to the audience, right? And so,
kind of this machine learning layer
orchestrates a lot of the things that,
you know, the people see in the app in
terms of paywalls and push
notifications, in-app messaging, etc.
etc. Eventually, you know, we see that
becoming a much deeper personalization
layer, you know, even personalizing
features in the app, but you know, we
kind of started from the growth revenue
layer.
>> I I think people sleep on just how
powerful things like that can be. You
know, you onboard a user, they probably
don't read half the stuff. Sometimes
you, you know, do a 60-page onboarding,
sometimes you only do a three. But once
they get into the app, it's like
done for a lot of apps. And one of the
one of the examples I've been using more
and more lately and and
podcast listeners will be familiar with
this one, but
huge fan of the Ladder fitness app. And
one of the coolest things they're able
to do, and again, I think people sleep
on these kind of opportunities, is that
they actively have their coaches,
because the whole point of Ladder is
like you have a personal coach on your
phone, they're actually like talking you
through the workouts and like planning
the workouts ahead. Each workout is
customized, they like record a script.
It's really an incredible product, but
then the coaches actually coach you on
how to use the app. They like remind you
to like set your weights and then they
tell you like it's important to set your
weights because then next time we do
this exercise, you'll know which one to
use.
And then they rolled out a big feature,
uh nutrition in the app. And so now the
coaches are all saying, "Hey, don't
forget to log your nutrition because no
matter how hard you work out, you're not
going to see the results you want
without getting your diet dialed in."
And it's really cool to see the the the
way they just kind of pull all of that
together to get the user to succeed. You
know, succeed in their lifting journey,
succeed in their health goals, succeed
in their diet goals. And it sounds like
that's similar to what you're building.
You don't have the luxury like lot and
not many apps have the luxury of that
kind of like a coach in their ear being
able to say things like that. But what
are some of the ways that you are
surfacing it in the app? The the like
feature education, the tips, are you,
you know, popping little banners? Is it
in a feed? Like what are all the ways
you're able to like, you know, push
those learnings into the app? And I I
think your situation's going to be a lot
more relatable to most apps than the
latter situation. So I'm excited to to
have this opportunity to ask you this
question.
>> I I think you know, there there is kind
of more mechanical aspect of it. For
example, we know like like every app,
the first 7 days of user are the most
important. We know, you know, there is a
very very high correlation between you
joining the app, creating or joining a
circle, inviting you know, other people
to eat or joining a circle, and then
being around on day seven and you being
around, you know, a year later, right?
And so, we know that if you're able to
make you understand the value of the app
in the first week, we have a long-term
users, right? And so, naturally from a
product and life cycle marketing
perspective, we have a series of
orchestrated steps like most apps,
right? Some of them are in onboarding,
some of them will be in mid-boarding. So
maybe on day two, we see that you
haven't used a feature, which may
you know, maybe you haven't looked at
location history, which is a very
popular feature. So we say, "Hey, do you
did you know that you can you can see
that?" And we use, you know, customize.
So if someone if John is in your circle,
you know, we can say something like,
"What was John up to yesterday?" right?
As as as things like that. So you can do
that for sure and that's you know, kind
of personalized and more and more we're
also targeting, you know, on on specific
behavior. And then the other thing is
that a lot of those things after a while
become noise because you know, users use
a lot of apps. You know, they don't
read. As as you said
nobody does, right?
And and so
you know, they kind of you know, they
tap tap tap and and they kind of become
noise. So, more and more we we want to
and we need to come up with fun unique
things. So, for example, we we launched
called something called a pet profile.
The pet profile is a set up a profile
for your dog or cat. Well, there are a
bunch of reasons for that. The main one
now is that if your dog runs away, you
can send a bat signal to your
neighborhood basically.
And all the Lighter 60 users will know
and and they kind of be on the lookout
for the dog, right? We got a really huge
success with that. A lot of people
created it. And the way we make people
aware of it is we call it peekaboo. We
basically we on app open there was a
animated dog popping up, you know, like
very cute and and asking you to to pet
him, right? To pet it. And so, you tap
on it and then you open the the feature,
right? And so, that worked really well.
>> Yeah, no, that's super smart. And you're
exactly right. Like
you know, the more kind of the more push
notifications you send, the more emails
you send, the more in-app banners you
drop down,
users do just become blind to it. So,
it's really cool to hear the success you
had with like a really creative approach
to that. And that's what it's going to
take. I mean, similarly it's like again,
Lighter has a unique advantage there,
but they're leveraging it, you know,
really well. And so, whatever unique
advantage or personality or whatever you
can bring into it is going to make it
more successful. And any other tips on
that front?
>> I think in you know, contextual prompts
uh useful prompts personalized and
targeted. If you can make it meaningful,
you know, rather than just tap here to
check out this feature, something about,
you know, their profile, something that
that is relevant to them. That's really
the way to go. You really need to cut
through the noise and make it very clear
why it's interesting, why it's cool, why
it's why it's fun.
>> That's awesome. And the cool thing, too,
is like with these AI tools, it's
hopefully going to get easier and easier
for even smaller apps and smaller teams
to do this kind of personalization at
scale where it's you know probably
taking y'all years and machine learning
team and data science team to get there.
I think it's going to get easier and
easier for smaller and smaller teams and
smaller and smaller apps to do this
level of personalization which is cool.
>> Yep. Exciting.
>> So the next thing I wanted to talk about
is your take on freemium. It's been such
a hot topic lately. We we've had guests
on the podcast talking about it recently
and then you know in the state of
subscription apps report we actually
shared a number that blew a lot of
people away myself included that hard
paywall apps convert users at five times
the rate of freemium apps and I think a
lot of people in the industry took that
as a you know hard paywall or die like
that's the only way to grow as a
subscription app and maybe that's true
of like smaller apps. But that's
obviously not true of an app at Life360
scale. So how do you think about
freemium?
>> So first it totally depends on on the
type of app, right? There are you know
some apps for which hard paywall apps
totally make sense. You know apps where
users are very high conviction, they're
not social, they don't benefit from
network effect, etc. etc. So that that
makes a lot of sense, right? For us it
you know we not only we are a freemium
app but our free tier is extremely
generous. I will say that for most
people it's good it's great it's good
enough, right? In fact the the reason
number one why people tell us they don't
subscribe is because they the free tier
is good enough. And uh our philosophy is
is that ideally we want to do something
about it but that something is not
making the free tier worse is trying to
provide more value and really diversify
the subscription offering, right? Uh
why? There are a few reasons. One is a
well, our company mission, you know,
we're really you know all about keeping
family safe and we have a lot of
features that are SOS and you know crash
detection etc. etc. that are literally
you know, life saving features in some
cases. And so, you know, making it you
know, accessible to everyone is a big
part of why we exist, really. But, the
second is
you know, we are and are the benefits
from network effect. In Life360 in solo
mode is is not really useful or
interesting, right? You need to invite
your family, invite your friends, etc.
etc. The number one way that people
discover us is parents telling other
parents, you know, about the app. Um and
so, you know,
our thesis is that having a large free
engage free user base around the world
is actually one of the big modes and one
of the
big competitive advantages for us. I
will also say that, you know, we have an
advertising business, so naturally there
is also a business incentive for us to
grow our free base. But, but it's
really, you know, the more people in
Life360, the more people invite more
people, the more people know about it,
the more features like the Petfinder
network or the Tile devices
or other official safety features that
we have in the app are useful. You know,
the more density of users. And so, you
know, for us it's all about that. That
said, you know, if you as I was saying
before, about 3% of our MAU
are subscribers, but on average about
four people use a subscription. So, it's
really more about 12% of our MAU that
are benefit for subscription, right?
Which is I would say in line with with a
lot of a lot of subscription apps. We
are able to
provide a good free experience, a great
free experience. And for sure we could,
you know, limit that and and grow
subscriber base much faster, but I think
that we will pay for that down the line
in slower growth and becoming a less
interesting product. Yeah, how do you
think about that? Like, how do you think
about when to add friction to the free
experience versus when to, like you
said, just just only think think adding
value? Well, yeah. So, adding friction
to the to the free experience we try not
to. Naturally, in some cases you have
to. For example, we have a we have a
paywall in in the in onboarding, right?
Like every like every other app. Sure,
it does add, you know, one screen of
friction, but not having that will uh
aware of will cut off a significant
amount of of other new subscribers,
right? We have a a um
a feature
uh that is uh location history where you
can
uh look uh at for the last, you know, 2
days for free users where people in your
circle were. 2 days is, you know, more
than enough for a lot of use cases. Uh
usually people want to see where people
were in the last day or so. Uh we did
some testing in the past. If you cut it
down to 6 hours or even 12 hours,
like we double the amount of subscribers
from the hook. So, you know, it would be
a sizable win. Uh a lot of company will
take that, but but we haven't uh because
it does make the feature significantly
less appealing for free users. And it
does make it less useful. And in some
cases it can make people less safe. So,
we decided not to do it. And uh you
know, we paid for it on short-term
bottom line, but we think in the long
term it's going to be, you know, the
right thing to do for our business.
>> It's so hard to balance the short-term
wins against the long-term strategy.
Um yeah, I mean I talked to the chief
product officer at Duolingo about this
when I chatted with him earlier this
year.
And they think along those same lines is
that, you know, I think he he called it
the premium trap is that you can easily
juice numbers and, you know, hit your
quarterly revenue by just locking more
and more features behind the premium
tier, but then you're really shooting
yourself in the foot long-term, but it's
so hard to get that balance right. Any
advice you have on like, you know, how
you think about how you differentiate
even even things like when you create a
new feature, what's the debate
internally whether it's a premium
feature or free feature? Like how do you
make those kind of decisions cuz it's so
hard?
>> Yeah, so it's a very interesting one and
is actually something that we've been
wrestling with because historically we
had uh
teams thinking about the free experience
and team which are you know um the ones
I work with now a lot thinking more
about the paid experience. And uh
that's actually not the right way um to
look at this because uh in most cases we
think that unless there is a a reason
and the reason is is usually cost. For
example, we offer roadside assistance to
our subscribers, right? We could not
offer roadside assistance to our free
users because you know every time they
they call it we pay for the toll, right?
And uh and so that's one where yes, is a
paid feature and I think that nobody
expect to get, you know, roadside
assistance for free, right? In some In
other cases
we think that every feature should be
premium. Meaning that
every feature that provides value to a
user should be great in the free version
of the feature itself and then it's up
to us find value, find additional value,
real value that we can provide as a
premium, right? And the challenge in
most cases is thinking of the mum part
of a premium not as an artificial gate,
you know, say I give you two for free
and then the rest is paid although some
features that we have worked that way.
But the the challenge that we we are
wrestling most times is how do we make
something free and then create a
completely new experience, a completely
new tier on top of that that is the that
is worth paying for, right?
And so the part of this is getting teams
that already always think about free to
think about
both and vice versa, right? And it's an
interesting, you you debate that we
have. There's no single question, but
we'll say
generally speaking, if something is very
expensive to provide,
it will become a premium feature.
If something is more of a software-based
feature, we start with free, we try to
build the best that we can, and then we
find a creative way to to build on top
of it.
>> How do you think about or measure how
that factors into long-term growth,
especially compared to like, you know,
customer acquisition and growth is like
a easy it's easier it's not easy these
days out post ATT, but it's easier to
measure, it's easier to see the numbers.
How are you tracking that like
subscriber value that you create? How
are you thinking about growing that and
its impact on revenue
when it's so much easier to track other
things?
>> I mean, there are definitely different
ways in which, you know, we we we track
value. The natural one is LTV, right?
And and so, like every company,
you know, we have an LTV model, you
know, that's all ever evolving. You
know, our case is quite complex because
you need to take a subscription into
consideration, you need to take device
sales into consideration, you need to
take advertising into consideration. If
you want to get fancy, you need to take
the the viral factor into consideration,
right?
And and so, it is a beast that is ever
evolving.
And
but definitely, you know, that that's
kind of, you know, the
the big one that that works, you know,
in the background and and we use it, you
know, then we attribute different
campaigns to it and so on etc. The
reality is that if you want to, you
know, narrow it down to subscription,
it's really a factor of how many users
we convert to subscription, what package
do they choose, silver, gold, or
platinum, they have naturally different
value and different economics,
and how long they stay subscribed,
right? And so, the reality the the job
is is quite straightforward in a sense
is get as many people as possible to
subscribe, direct them to the best
package for them, and then try to keep
them subscribed as long as possible.
>> It is such a shame. I I do feel like
there's a lot of apps that get to this
kind of place product-wise
where it's like they hit product market
fit and then they just put all the gas
into growth and top of funnel and aren't
putting as much effort, attention, focus
into
continuing to like increase that value
over time. And so it's really cool to
hear that as a kind of primary focus of
the company, not just, you know, that
top-line growth where it's it's easier
to see, but it doesn't build that
momentum that really compounds over
time. Earlier you mentioned um how
Life360 really is better with a family,
with uh as a couple, uh with a friend
group or something. How do you think
about Life360 as that kind of almost a
social app? Um
versus like a standard, I know you've
worked on a lot of subscription apps in
your career. Uh so how how does it
differ and how do you think about that?
>> It's interesting, I think, because we're
not a social app, right? We're not a
social network. We're not a place where
you can actually, you know, communicate
with people outside of your core circle
or, you know, you can communicate
explicitly in a match. You can you can
send emojis and things like that. You
can check on people, you know, but there
you know, there's no explicit
communication. There are no big viral
kind of mechanic, right? It is not an
app where, I don't know, you you you
you're going to share your location on
X, you know, for everyone to see where
you are, right? And so it's a it's a
it's a social app in the sense that the
circle, which is often a family, um but
can be a anything really, is the unit,
right? Is it is equally the core unit.
And as I was saying, a paying circle on
average is about four people. A circle
on average is about people. It changes
everything we
we do. It doesn't just change
monetization. It doesn't change the way
we we think about growth. For example,
if we launch if we think of a new
feature, often we know the conversation
will be
you know, we have an idea for this
feature, and say, "Okay, well, that's a
good idea, but I don't know, Snapchat
has something similar, or
uh Instagram has something similar. You
know, how is our different? You know,
and often the the the answer is, "Well,
because we provide a value to the circle
in this way, in that way, in that way,
right?" And so, it kind of it makes
things harder, in a way, because you're
a bit more constrained
in what you can do to grow, but it also
provides clarity in other ways, because
it makes it easier to understand this is
something that we should be doing or not
be doing. This is how we build something
that is, you know, really unique to us.
>> How do you think about and measure the
those halo effects? Cuz you talked
about, like, on average, only one person
is subscribing for four people using.
Are you watching those individual users
who aren't the subscriber that when when
it goes from four to two, is that like a
a signal that the one subscriber is
potentially going to churn? Like, I
imagine it adds a lot of kind of
complexity into kind of understanding
usage patterns and retention and
subscriber retention.
>> You know, we without going into a lot of
detail, but what I what I can say is
that there is a certain circle size
three to four people that has
significantly higher conversion and
retention than lower and higher circle
sizes, right? And so,
uh higher circle sizes is often friend
groups,
uh or things like extended family, or
they're probably less motivated to pay
for safety features. And the lower
circle sizes, yes, they're either
couples or maybe groups that, you know,
maybe the kids, you know, one thing that
we that one one big churn reason that we
have is, you know, the kids left.
They're in college.
And
you know, and that's basically for some
families at least the end of the Life360
circle, right? It's really about you
know, how their their needs and how
their their life changes.
>> Yeah. Well, that's great that the pet
feature, right? So, when the kids leave
house and now you've
you're extending that runway by
tracking their pet instead of the kids.
>> Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
>> I I did want to dig into that actually
because you know, it it is fairly unique
as a company in that you have physical
products that you sell, the Tile uh
brand that was that Life360 purchased,
um which really cool now is um the Apple
Find My compatible and all those things.
So, that's really fantastic product. And
then now the pet product that was
released not too long ago. How do you
think about incorporating those physical
products both as a kind of top of
funnel, but then also as like a way to
increase the LTV of a user. And then
layered on another thing to increase the
retention by getting them to track their
pet and things like that. There's these
kind of layer on a lot of
the the those physical products can like
fill a lot of roles. How do you think
about those?
>> Yeah, absolutely. We see it's all of
that. So, naturally there is a top of
funnel effect, right? You you buy a pet
GPS which is a pet tracker or you buy a
Tile which is a Bluetooth line of
Bluetooth trackers. And then you know,
you
sign up to like 360 you become a user.
Uh in some cases like with pet GPS you
you need to be a subscriber to to use
it. And uh that's naturally you know,
user acquisition and subscriber
acquisition which is which is always
always a good thing. Sometimes we bundle
some offers in the apps. When you when
you subscribe, you know, we say, "Hey,
do you want a free Tile?" Or things like
that. You know, that with certain users
that helps in converting. But then yeah,
there is a retention um
consideration. We know from data that
people with Tiles retain better overall
than people without Tiles simply because
the basis they have the same use case
and they lay a Tile on top of it and so
it becomes more useful, right?
And also
there is a there is a matter as you as
you mentioned of prolonging the usage
cycle, I will say, of the app. So,
people use our trackers on younger kids,
for example, right? And maybe younger
kids don't have a phone
and
you know, you can put a Tile in the
backpack
and you know, have some peace of mind.
You use the pet GPS even when your kids
go to college, you know, your dog is
still there, so you're going to still
using it, right? We are more and more
doing work on the aging parent segment.
I don't know if you're familiar with the
this concept of the sandwich generation,
you know, which is you know, people in
their 40s or so that they have kids,
they have parents that are aging, so you
worry about your kids, you worry about
your parents, and so you know, the idea
is can we you know, provide solutions
for all of it, right? And naturally, you
know, it's because, you know, we want to
provide safety, it's also because if
we're able to provide you with a a good
series of services from when your kids
are young to when they grow up, for your
parents, your pets, then I think we have
a very good product.
>> I had the the Skylight
calendar folks on earlier this year. One
of the things they talked about was that
they actually do make a pretty good
profit on the devices themselves
and then later on the subscription
revenue on top of that. Is that how
things are done at Life360 or like how
do you view the profit margins of the
hardware compared to the subscriptions?
Do you view that as a loss leader that
drives the subscriptions or as a profit
center itself?
>> to the ecosystem and subscription is the
main
you know revenue driver over time but
it's it's not a loss leader I mean we
don't necessarily lose money on the
device business but I would say that
it's a way to strengthen the ecosystem
for us.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it's tough to to balance
that though. Yeah, it's like yeah, how
much profit cuz it the lower you can get
the price the more you can bring that
top of funnel in through the devices but
then yeah, you have to like fight both
sides so it makes sense that it's a it's
a tough balance.
>> I will say that we will always index
toward trying to reach more users with
the devices and bring more users in the
ecosystem versus trying to maximize the
the margins of the devices.
>> We've been talking a bit about, you
know, how important the app is to
family. How are you thinking about the
growth of that? Like as you think about
use cases and so I'm not not asking you
to like you know, share future roadmap
plans or anything like that but I know
you've kind of been slowly evolving it
away from like just being a tracking app
to be to having other uses and actually
I'd love for you to explain this cuz I
didn't dig super deep into it but you
recently partnered with Uber on a
feature
and I know you're starting to think
about the Life 360 app more and more as
this kind of family super app not just a
tracking app. So like what are the steps
you've taken so far and how do you
broadly think about that without delving
into future plans or anything?
>> First of all, say that you know, it is a
stated goal of ours to become the family
super app but we're very early.
We have things in flight and naturally
and ideas that I cannot go through on
future plans but I can tell you um it
did the way we we approach it and then
maybe I can tell you a bit about Uber.
It's really about what problems can we
solve for families that are adjacent to
what we do today
and that solve a real a real pain point,
right? And so naturally we you know, we
have you know, 100 million monthly
active users. We hear from them a lot.
We know what they need. We know we know
what they tell us. Explicitly they tell
us, oh, I wish Life 360 was also doing X
or implicitly because you know, we see
the data, we we we know we talked to
them. There are, you know, patterns that
we see that because I think we we we
have opportunities, you know, in in
other sectors. So, you know, we're
really about
family safety and peace of mind. That my
first safety and peace of mind doesn't
just mean location. There are a lot of,
you know, ways to look at it. And then
there are, you know, additional, I would
say, opportunities that that still
leverage location.
Family coordination is one, right? Our
users tell us, "Oh, I wish Life123 was
helping me make sense of my kids'
schedule, for example." Maybe there are
things that we can do there, right? Or
I wish Life123 was was helping, you
know, my aging dad
be protected from scams. I just made,
you know, two random examples, right?
But there are many things that kind of
either fit in the realm of family safety
or of location
that, you know, probably we can take a
look at, right? And I think the the the
main thing there is to be disciplined
and really understanding are we solving
a real problem? We have permission to
solve this problem, and is there a big
overlap with our existing audience,
right? Versus just, you know, putting
stuff in the app and and making it
become bloated.
>> Yeah, well, that that was actually my
exact follow-up question was it is it
implicitly a kind of filter that if it's
not an obvious feature that should go
into the app, then we're we probably
shouldn't go in that direction. Like if
it would make sense to have to build a
whole separate second app, it makes less
sense or is that something that that
Yeah, okay.
I I think very few companies have suc-
success, you know, developing a second
app, you know, no mat- no matter the
size of your first, right? Yeah, even
Duolingo, when I had him on the podcast,
he was talking about how they originally
thought they were going to build out
like 20 different apps, and they
launched, I think it was either chess or
math as a separate app, and then they
had to bring it back into the main app.
So, yeah, even even Duolingo tried, and
you think if anybody could succeed with
two different apps, it would be Duolingo
and nope.
>> Yeah, absolutely. This is all yes. And
and in Italy, you know, at that point
that orchestration commented earlier
before because it's super important
because the the more things you put in
the app, the more important is to show
the right things to the right people at
the right time, right?
And so, you know, that's that's where we
we have a lot of thinking to do and it's
definitely going to be interesting. But
the goal is definitely we want to become
as useful as possible to as many
families as possible.
>> And that's how you drive the value which
then drives the LTV which then drives
the word of mouth and drives all the all
the things. So, yeah, it makes a ton of
sense. I I wanted to get back to the
monetization side of things and you kind
of mentioned briefly that ads, you know,
do bring revenue from the free users.
So, it's not that your freemium product
is just about the social sharing and
things like that, but you're actually
making revenue. And then recently, you
actually acquired an app ad platform to
start doing more and more of that
internally. How how do y'all think about
balancing that? And and and I'll I'll go
back to kind of what we were talking
about before, too. Like it would be easy
to put more and more and more ads into
the free experience and then make it
worse and worse and worse, but that's
obviously not the approach that you're
taking. So, how do how do you balance
the ad monetization and and making it
still a good experience and and all
those things?
>> Yeah, I mean, really good question,
right? And I would say it took a long
time for Life 360 to get into the ad
business. If you think the company has
been around I think 15 years or so and
only in the last 2 years really we
started we started working in ads. So,
the
kind of
baseline is do no harm, meaning keep
make sure that the ads are not
intrusive, not invasive, and they're not
unwelcome by the audience. You know, in
Italy, you know, you measure that there
you know, the qualitative and
quantitative standpoint. You know, look
at attention, you can engagement, and
you talk to users, etc. etc. So, that's
that's kind of the
the baseline. But then the the the the
one that I think is more interesting
thing building towards
is uh
how do we use all the data that we have
or you know the knowledge that we have
to actually provide value to users,
right? So, Uber will be an example. Uber
started as a partnership on
landing notification product that we
built. And that that's a product we
built for users, right? We built it
just a because it was actually a
hackathon product project.
>> Oh, nice.
>> Uh and so we we we we ship it and so
basically when you land uh
in for people in your circle that you
landed, right? So, it's a peace of mind
feature that people love and Uber
approached us and said, "Oh, we saw
this. What if then we could also ask if
you want to call a Uber?"
When you land at the airport, it makes a
lot of sense, right? And so that that
basically was started the partnership,
right? And now they have this Uber team
product and so we we're you know about
to launch partnership with them in the
sense. So, those are just things that
make sense, right?
You know, you as a family you get value
through it, you know, uh
and you get discounts, special offers,
etc. And they make a lot of sense for
what you do, right? Think of uh you know
we know for example when someone is
going to Costco, right? And you know,
there are a lot of opportunities that
you know to be useful there. Uh not just
by popping an ad but I by you know
giving you an offer that is tailored to
you for example, right? And so that's
the kind of things that I think are
interesting and uh that we can focus on.
The other thing that we did in Nativo,
acquisition, the company that we bought
earlier this year we're expanding our
targeting outside of our 360.
And so that means that you know, both in
terms of the data that we receive and
where we can target those ads, they also
go beyond our platform, right? We become
more of a network in the sense.
>> I love the way you're thinking about
that and I think a lot of people there
is just this like negative perception
around ads. Like "Oh, yeah, they get in
the way, like they take up real estate,
they're ugly." Yeah, I've talked about
it on the podcast. I have a weather app
and it used to be freemium and I used to
have ads and I got so many complaints
about ads cuz it was like guns and
casinos and like, you know, really
flashy annoying things that really took
away from the product experience. But,
like over the last few years, I've come
to really appreciate like I actually
enjoy
scrolling Instagram in part because of
the ads. Like they're kind of a product
recommendation engine. And I mean,
specifically, you know, if I'm shopping
for a new hat, I'll go into Instagram
and like search hat and look at a few
hats and then all of a sudden I like all
the best, you know, hat ads. And so I
think, you know, I I think it is a
mindset shift and and it is something
that as a whole industry we need to get
better at the all of tech industry
really needs to get better at like
finding ways for the ads to actually add
value and be enjoyable and contextual
and relevant and helpful versus just
being this annoyance. And so it sounds
like that's that's what you're building.
It's like you're you're building toward
ads not just being this annoyance that
people are going to subscribe to get rid
of, but something actually enhances the
experience over time.
>> Yeah, for sure, for sure. And and think
how many very successful apps that are
that are, as you say, this
basically ads, you know, all those apps
that offer first discounts, coupons,
etc., etc. They're super super popular,
right? And those are essentially ads,
right? But people use them because you
know, that you know, they get the value
out of it, right? So So I think that's
the key.
>> All right. Well, as we wrap up, I I do
ask every guest now three questions. So
the first one is, what is the most
impactful experiment or change you
implemented in the last year? Your
biggest biggest win of the last year.
>> I'll talk about maybe one of the machine
learning targeted experiments that we we
did because it was actually surprising
how well it worked for a specific
reason. So, as I as I mentioned, we have
three tiers, silver, gold, and platinum.
The majority of users choose gold, which
I I will say is
you know, is great for for most people.
Platinum has you know, additional
feature that is a much wider range for
roadside assistance, for example. So, if
you drive a lot, it's a good deal.
There is identity protection. There are
a bunch of other other services that we
offer, right? So, it's sometimes hard to
explain it. People rotate to kind of the
mid-tier pricing product. You know, in a
paywall you often cannot show all of it.
So, you know, you just show the one the
most people will will will go for,
right? And so, we use machine learning
to
target platinum to people that we
thought, based on data, based on
previous experiments, based on our
profile, we have about 900 kind of data
points that we use for that. People that
we thought had a higher propensity to to
subscribe to to platinum. It doubled the
percentage of new users that subscribing
to platinum. So, that was already very
very good. But he did that without
losing a single gold subscriber, which
was super surprising.
>> It's incredible.
>> He basically found new users, right?
And that would
that maybe we were presenting with gold
and they would not like gold enough.
And now we're presenting them with
platinum and they like platinum and they
subscribe to platinum, right? And so,
that that's an example of how using
machine learning, you know, was really
transformative and and and give some
surprising upside.
>> Yeah. Oh, that's great. And at at
Life360's scale, I imagine that was a a
pretty big financial win as well.
Um all right, the next one I actually
one of my favorite questions to ever ask
is what's the worst experiment, the
biggest fail that you've had in the last
year?
>> Yeah, so this is not from this year, but
from from last year, but you know, still
still you know, pretty pretty recent.
Well, one I I mentioned to you really,
which is when we experimented with
taking away value from uh
it that that's actually earlier than
that. And it that's actually funny, so
I'll I'll I'll tell you and then tell
you something but I'll tell you this one
because it's funny.
I was like 6 months into the job, right?
And I do this experiment and I saw the
numbers and I was like you know,
like the number were very big, right? In
in terms of revenue upside, you know?
And
so, I you know, I I run back to the
exact team you know, like with
we're going to we're going to be rich.
And and instead of like telling me,
"Yeah, this is great, etc. etc." I I
basically, you know, go go yell that.
And so, that that was my kind of my my
education into how things are done at
Life360.
>> When I had Chris on the podcast, Chris
Halls, the the former CEO who's now the
chairman and still super involved, he
talked about the the the freemium bill
of rights that they're inside Life360,
there is like core things that they you
should never touch.
So, you So, I'm assuming it was like one
of those core things and you you were
going to like take it away from free
users?
>> Correct. Correct. Correct. They didn't
tell you, you know, you know, I I
learned, you know,
at the end I I understood why, but it
was pretty striking, you know, as
someone that used to, you know, just
make the number go up.
You know.
So, that was that was kind of a really
funny one.
Recently, well, you know, we we've been
kind of
in success a lot of losses in trying to
drive virality, you know, beyond the
circle creation and joining in the app.
So, basically getting people we know
people do it outside of the app. Parents
go, you know, pick up school pick up on
the the school chat or or whatever, they
talk and and that's why people find us.
But we know and so, we wanted to
replicate that in the app, right? Which
makes sense. It's like 40% of users tell
us they found us because someone else
told them about the app and then then
great, let's put a button in the app
where people can do that in the app and
it's going to be my much easier, I know,
and maybe we we say, "Hey, you can you
can gift a silver subscription. You can
get yourself a silver subscription." You
know, different things, right? You know,
nothing. Nothing. Really really you
know, failure across the board. And and
the reason is people my age or or
families or older people are not viral,
you know? Parents are not viral.
And and
And so, you know, the the one that are
viral are their kids, right? But their
kids are not usually the core audience
of our app. They're on the app, but the
decision being on the app is made by the
parents, right? And and so, that has
been a a series of successes for us.
>> All right, last question as we wrap up.
As a fill-in-the-blank, growth would be
easier if
>> I I will go back to what I I said at the
start. If every team
thought of itself as a growth team, then
growth would be easier.
>> That's awesome. That's such a such a
great way to wrap up the podcast as
well.
I did want to give you an opportunity
though to to shout out any specific job
roles. I mean, having this conversation
with you and having talked to Chris last
year, I mean, it just sounds like such a
great company who really cares about its
people and the people it's serving. So,
yeah, if you're in the industry and want
to work for a great company, definitely
check out the careers page. But anything
specific you want to shout out?
>> I I would say we have a lot of roles
open now. You will see a lot of roles in
our career page as AI native, which is
very exciting. What does it mean? It
means that basically you're
expected to come in, you know, find your
your full things, understand what's
going on, understand the company, and
then you're given an outcome, and you're
told to go and do it. And build your own
tools, and find ways to do it, and kind
of really lead this AI transformation.
So, those are very exciting roles. I
will say that you know, we're growing
fast. It's a bunch of really passionate,
collaborative people.
It's very dynamic. It's fun. And uh
something that I think is worth doing.
Uh you know, we we hear that from
families every day.
>> Yeah, you're you're literally saving
lives.
>> Once in a while, yes. But most of the
time we we most of the time we're
telling people that their kids are late
at school.
Which Which is still
Yes, but still useful.
>> Yeah, yeah, that's awesome. Well, this
has been a blast. I don't think I've
laughed this much on a podcast maybe
ever. Um these last few stories were
great. But thank you so much for joining
me. This is a blast.
>> Thank you very much, David. Thank you
for having me, and talk to you soon.
>> Thanks so much for listening.
If you have a minute, please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player.
You can also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.